com.de 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy | .com.de

Protecting your privacy is very important to CentralNic. Data processing and usage is based exclusively on the basis of the legal requirements. Please take the time to carefully read this Privacy Policy. We will explain in detail what personal data is collected and how we’re using such data. It is recommended that you keep a printout of the Privacy Policy for your record.

### 1\. Collection, processing and use of personal data when accessing our website

You can visit our website without giving us any information about yourself. We will only store data without reference to individuals such as the name of your Internet Service Provider, the page that you are visiting from or the name of the requested webpage. These data will be analyzed to further improve our services and won’t allow any conclusion on your person.

Other than that, personal data will not be processed, unless you expressly consented into such further processing.

### 2\. Cookie Usage

On several pages, we use cookies to make our website more attractive to visit and to further improve specific functions. These are small text files that are stored on your computer. Most of our cookies are deleted from your hard disk after closing your respective browser session (so-called session cookies). Other cookies may remain on your computer and allow us, to recognize your machine on your next visit (so-called persistent cookies).

The following types of cookies are used on our website:

  * __utmz tracks where a visitor came from (search engine, search keyword, link) 
  * __utma tracks each user's amount of visits, and the time of the first, the previous, and the current visit.
  * __utmb and __utmc are used to track how long you stay on a site - when a visit starts and approximately ends.

You may refuse to store cookies by changing the settings on your browser. However, we would like to point out, that you may not able to use all features of this website when doing so.

### 3\. Collection, processing and use of personal data in using our services

Personal data is only collected if you provide such data to us voluntarily for gaining access to specific services. Personal date provided by you without your prior consent (section 4) will be used only for providing our services, namely the facilitation of domain registrations of the TLD “.com.de”.

### 3a. Data we are interested in your domain registration charge for

Under "Signup for a domain”, you will have the opportunity to tell us that you are interested in registering a specific domain. We would like to ask you to provide us with your e-mail address and the domain name, which you want to register.

### 3b. How does CentralNic use this data?

After closing the so-called "sunrise period", ie a possibility for trademark holder to register a specific domain name, we will use your e-mail address as well as the domain name, which you’ve told us, to inform you if and where the desired domain can be registered. No further usage of that data will take place. After receiving the above mentioned e-mail, the respective data will be deleted.

### 4\. Consented data usage

A more extensive collection, processing or use of your personal information without your consent does not occur.

The user has the option to order a newsletter under „News". This newsletter will provide you with news & alerts about .com.de on an irregular basis. To receive our newsletter we would like to ask you for your email address.

After receiving your e-mail address, we would like to ask you for your confirmation, which is needed, so that we can make sure, that you actually want to receive our newsletter. To do so, just click a link that you find in the confirmation email. Then you will receive another confirmation email. From now on, you will receive our newsletter.

Of course you can cancel your subscription at any time. You will find a link in every newsletter. Just by clicking that link, you can tell us that you do not like to receive further newsletters from us.

### 5\. Disclosure of personal data 

A transfer of personal data will not take place without prior consent by the respective user.

### 6\. Rights

You have a right to information about your stored data, and the right to correct, block or delete such data. To do so, please contact our Data Protection Officer (section 7).

### 7\. Questions about Data Security

Please contact info@centralnic.com if you have questions about the collection, processing or use of your personal information, the disclosure, correction, blocking or deletion of data and revocation of consents granted.

### 8\. Changing the Privacy Policy

As our website, through the implementation of new technologies and / or the extension of our services, might change from time to time, we will need to change this privacy policy to reflect such changes. CentralNic reserves the right to change this policy at any time for the future. Therefore we recommend that the user reads this privacy policy on each visit.

Privacy policy last updated April 2011
